VINCENT WANG

- vwang29@my.bcit.ca
- in linkedin.com/in/wang-vincent/
- github.com/vwparadox/
- Richmond, B.C., Canada
- <u>vwparadox.github.io/portfolio/</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

The combination of my technology skills and 3 years of UX design and product management experience in Agile development practices strengthens my understanding of programming-based business operations. This allows me to start my contributions to the company on day 1.

EDUCATIONBritish Colubia Institute of Technology

Dip. Computer Systems 2020-2022

- GPA: 92%
- Course Taken: Python, Web Dev, Project, Business Communication, Business Analysis & System Design, Math, Relational Database, Web Graphic Design
- Studying Java and C extensively this term, expected to be fluent in both by April 2021

University of British Columbia BA History 2011-2015

• Skills Acquired: Research and Analytics, Academic Writing

OTHER INFO

Languages: English & Chinese (Mandarin/Cantonese)

Work Eligibility: Canada & US (Dual

Citizenship)

Hobbies: Badminton, Kareoke & Games

SKILLS SUMMARY

Technical Skills: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sass, Bootstrap, React, Node.js SQL, MongoDB, Git/Github, Photoshop, Axure RP

Non-Technical Skills: UX Design, Digital Product Management, Collaboration and Communication in both English & Chinese

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Library Management System with Python Nov 2020

- Developed a text-based library management system that allowed users to search books by keywords or move books
- Set restrictions to ensure books can only be moved between valid locations. Users could save their changes by reading/writing the modified records on a txt file.
- Performed unit tests and doctests to ensure functionality without errors.

HomeWork To-Do List App

Oct 2020

- Collaborated with a group of 5, provided designs in program functionality, Workflow, UX, and database for app.
- Facilitated team meetings and lead discussions regarding the overall strategic planning of our project.

OPSTEEL Steel Trading Platform

2017-2018

- In a Product Management team of 10, designed and managed functional requirements of the platform website.
- Refined purchase workflow process of the platform, resulting in enhanced effectiveness and improved UX.

Portfolio Website with React

Jan 2021

- Developed a personal portfolio website from scratch with self-learned React.js.
- Responsive and Dynamic: includes interactive visual effects, Carousel rotations, and particle effects, and 3D effects.
- Technology Used: React.js, Node.js React-Bootstrap, GitHub pages.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Product Manager

Shanghai Yidu Technology Co.,Ltd. July 2017 -August 2019

- Designed and Managed requirements of projects in Agile development iterations with platforms similar to Jira.
- Improved UX designs of the overall architecture for the company's main product, including E-commerce trading platforms and online supply chain platforms
- Participate in gray-box testings before and after iterations were launched in the production environment to ensure requirements are met

Digital Product Management Intern

Shanghai Yidu Technology Co.,Ltd. July 2016 -June 2017

- Designed demo prototypes with Axure RP and/or Balsamiq
- Produced product requirement document (PRD).